MOHAMMED ELMOJTABA

Software Engineer

+249 124254998 Sudan-Khartoum

@ mhmdfrj.97@gmail.com

http://portfolio-notmhmd.vercel.app/

EXPERIENCE

Backend Engineer (Part-Time)

Medan

05/2022 - Ongoing

Fintech Company

- Maintaining Company Back-end infrastructures from web servers
- Developing And Maintaining Next-Gen Payment Solution
- Implemented a container based development environment which reduced developer on-boarding setup time by 90%
- Key Technologies: Python, Docker, PostgreSQL, Auth0, Swagger, Blockchain, Linux Administration

Backend Engineer (Part-Time)

Saudi Arabia Based Startup

- Maintaining multitenancy property management web service using python
- Worked with technical leads and other team members to ensure 100% ontime delivery in every sprint
- Implementing new features that meets the business needs
- Using TDD (Test Driven Development) approach to produce efficient maintainable code
- Implementing Efficient Restful API
- Key Technologies: Python, Docker, Redis, RabbitMQ, Kubernetes, PostgreSQL, Auth0, Keycloak, Swagger, Open-ID, YAML, Git-Lab CI/CD, Google Cloud

Frontend Engineer

Holdings Company focused on investing in, full-service, integrated solutions

- Developing, deploying and maintaining web application using angular framework
- Planning Software projects that meets the business needs
- Consulting with the UI/UX team to improve user experience
- Key Technologies: Angular, Typescript, Firebase, Google Maps, Figma

Frontend Engineer

Altkamul Altiqani

progressive software company focused on providing smart services

- Document and maintain software functionality
- Programming well-designed, testable, efficient code
- Troubleshoot, debug and upgrade existing systems
- Developing and maintaining both mobile and web apps based on business requirements
- Completed 6 different projects we worked on
- Key Technologies: Angular, Ionic, Typescript, One-signal, Firebase, Google Maps, Cordova, Capacitor

SUMMARY

Goal Oriented Software Engineer With More Than Four Years Experience In Software Development, Build And Maintained Mobile And Web Apps, Proficient With Building And Deploying Web Application Using Python Diango And Angular, Familiar With DevOps and Containerization using Docker and Orchestration them using Kubernetes.

LANGUAGES

Arabic Native			
English Proficient			

SKILLS				
Angular	django	Docker		
Linux Adm	ninstartion			
Problem S	olving K	Subernetes		
RxJS JavaScript TypeScript				
NestJS	PostgreSG	QL Python		
RabbitMQ	Redis			
Software	Developme	nt SASS		
Web Appli	ication			
Django RE	ST framewo	ork lonic		
DevOps	HTML	Tailwind CSS		

PROJECTS

Ajjer Web Service

https://www.ejjir.com/

Short summary of your work

· Ejjer is a web service that manages property and reservation and provide users with a friendly UI, and integrated With different online travel agencies like booking and airbnb and more

EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Engineer

Horizon Omega

1 01/2019 - 01/2020

Responsibilities: Build and deployed and maintained mobile apps using Angular Framework

Key Technologies: Angular, Ionic, Typescript, One-signal, Firebase, Google Maps, Cordova, Capacitor

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Software Engineering

Neelain University

1 01/2014 - 12/2022

ACHIEVEMENTS



Fresh Mobile Application

Fresh is a sales service of vegetables and fruits - and other products - carefully selected at the central market prices with home delivery at a nominal price developed using ionic 3 framework. LINK



Django Movie Recommendation

movie recommendation service that applies ML (Machine Learning) to recommend movies to the users using cosine similarity. LINK

PROJECTS

Yalla Wash Mobile Application

https://www.yallawash.ae/

Short summary of your work

• Yallawash is UAE'S First on-demand app that connects to the auto services world instantly.

SMS Charity Web Application

http://www.altkamul.ae/Services/sms-charity.html

Short summary of your work

· SMS Charity is web based sms charity application that utilize the power of the web to allow users to donate through SMS.

> CV Enhancy Powered by